// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "It is another type of Earth movement that forms cracks or fractures on the rocks",
    answer: "A. Tension",
    options: [
      "A. Tension",
      "B. Faulting",
      "C. Faulting",
      "D. Compression",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "It is a type of Earth movement resulting from the compression of rock",
    answer: "D. Compression",
    options: [
      "A. Tension",
      "B. Faulting",
      "C. Faulting",
      "D. Compression",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "A one-sided slope connecting two horizontal or gently inclined strata",
    answer: "A. Monocline",
    options: [
      "A. Monocline",
      "B. Syncline",
      "C. Anticline",
      "D. Overturned",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "It is an upward fold on the rock.",
    answer: "C. Anticline",
    options: [
      "A. Monocline",
      "B. Syncline",
      "C. Anticline",
      "D. Overturned",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "It happens when rock is being squeezed due to compression force. This type of fault generally moves up.",
    answer: "C. Reverse (convergent) fault",
    options: [
      "A. Monocline",
      "B. Transform (strike-slip) fault",
      "C. Reverse (convergent) fault",
      "D. Normal (divergent) fault",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "It is a process in which sedimentary rocks are arranged in layers due to crustal movement, displacement of soils, and distortion of terrain.",
    answer: "B. Stratification",
    options: [
      "A. Compression",
      "B. Stratification",
      "C. Tension",
      "D. Expansion",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The following are examples of igneous rocks EXCEPT:",
    answer: "D. Marble",
    options: [
      "A. Basalt",
      "B. Pumice",
      "C. Granite",
      "D. Marble",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which is an example of sedimentary rocks?",
    answer: "A. Conglomerate",
    options: [
      "A. Conglomerate",
      "B. Slate",
      "C. Basalt",
      "D. Granite",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "It is a type of rock which is formed when other rocks are changed by heat, pressure, and chemical reaction.",
    answer: "C. Metamorphic",
    options: [
      "A. Sedimentary",
      "B. Igneous",
      "C. Metamorphic",
      "D. Stratified rock",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "It is a type of rock which is formed through solidified molten rock.",
    answer: "B. Igneous",
    options: [
      "A. Sedimentary",
      "B. Igneous",
      "C. Metamorphic",
      "D. Stratified rock",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "It is the process in which sedimentary rocks are arranged in layers.",
    answer: "C. Stratification",
    options: [
      "A. Metamorphism",
      "B. Compression",
      "C. Stratification",
      "D. Tension",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "It is a process in which rocks are continuously transformed between the three rock types igneous, sedimentary and metamorphic.",
    answer: "A. Rock Cycle",
    options: [
      "A. Rock Cycle",
      "B. Stratification",
      "C. Compression",
      "D. Layers of rocks",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "It is a type of rock which is formed when other rocks are changed by heat, pressure, and chemical reaction.",
    answer: "C. Metamorphic",
    options: [
      "A. Sedimentary",
      "B. Igneous",
      "C. Metamorphic",
      "D. Stratified rock",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "It contains information about the relative ages of events and objects in Earthâ€™s history.",
    answer: "B. Stratification",
    options: [
      "A. Rock Cycle",
      "B. Stratification",
      "C. Compression",
      "D. Layers of rocks",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "It is a type of rock which is formed through solidified molten rock.",
    answer: "B. Igneous",
    options: [
      "A. Sedimentary",
      "B. Igneous",
      "C. Metamorphic",
      "D. Stratified rock",
    ],
  },
];
